<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Gaming news</string>
    <string name="God_of_war"> God of War is an action-adventure game franchise created by David Jaffe at Sony Santa Monica Studio. It began in 2005 on the PlayStation 2 video game console, and has become a flagship title for the PlayStation brand, consisting of eight games across multiple platforms with a ninth currently in development.God of War fans will soon be able to play the latest game in the series on PC. This will come as a huge deal to players who have been following the main character’s Kratos’ tale since the early God of War games, which have all up to this point been exclusive to consoles.

“We’re thrilled to announce that God of War (2018) will be coming to PC on January 14, 2022!” Sony Santa Monica Studio senior community manager Grace Orlady wrote.

“All of us at Santa Monica Studio have been humbled by the immense amount of support and passions fans of the God of War series have shown in the latest chapter of Kratos’ story since its release. As of August 2021, 19.5MM copies for God of War on PlayStation 4 have been sold through and we can’t wait to share that experience with a whole new group of players on PC.”</string>
    <string name="overwatch">Activision Blizzard today revealed in its quarterly earnings report that it would be delaying the release of Overwatch 2 and Diablo IV.

The company was not specific on exactly how long the games would be delayed, but neither game will be released in 2022. It simply said that the games would receive “a later launch … than originally envisaged.” The given reason is that the development teams require more time with the games in order to adequately support them after launch.

Activision Blizzard said in a statement: “These are two of the most eagerly anticipated titles in the industry, and our teams have made great strides towards completion in recent quarters. But we believe giving the teams some extra time to complete production and continue growing their creative resources to support the titles after launch will ensure that these releases delight and engage their communities for many years into the future.”

Mike Ybarra, in the earnings call, attributed part of the delays to the changes in leadership on both development teams. Chacko Sonny, the executive producer of the Overwatch series at Blizzard, and Luis Barriga, the director of Diablo IV, both left the company this year.</string>
    <string name="gta">A new update on GTA 6 has good news about the release date of the next Grand Theft Auto game from Rockstar Games. This week, a rumor has been circulating claiming that GTA 6 was in development hell, which is industry language for going terribly. To this end, it was claimed that the games development was rebooted in 2020. What does this mean? Well, it means the game is not releasing anytime soon, and when it does release, it may have serious problems, as games that go through development hell often do. That said, Grand Theft Auto fans dont need to worry because the claims the rumor makes are inaccurate due to a mistranslation.

The rumor was reported by many, all of whom sourced Rockstar Magazine, a French outlet with a reliable track record. However, the video that was sourced was mistranslated according to the source. Commenting on the rumor circulated in their name, Rockstar Magazine Chris Klippel noted that he never said that GTA 6 was in development hell and was rebooted, but rather simply speculated this. Could the falsified claim still be true? Sure, but it also was never made. And the moment of publishing, none of the usual sources have claimed Grand Theft Auto VI is in development hell or that its development was rebooted in 2020, so theres little reason to believe this speculation is accurate.

As you would expect, Rockstar Games nor its parent company, Take-Two Interactive have commented on any of this. We do not expect this to change for a wide range of reasons, but if it does, we will be sure to update the story accordingly.</string>
    <string name="halo">Halo Infinite may end up releasing earlier than expected. While the games official launch date is poised to transpire early next month, it seems apparent that 343 Industries and Xbox Game Studios are planning to release the latest entry in the long-running Halo series a bit sooner. However, this earlier launch date will surely have to be something that fans will need to pay for if they want to play Halo Infinite as soon as possible.

Within the past day, a new page appeared on the Microsoft Store for an Early Access Digital Bundle of Halo Infinite. Details of this listing were sparse, but the name alone seems to suggest that Xbox and 343 will be releasing a version of Halo Infinite that will give players access to the game prior to its official launch date. This is a trend that a number of publishers have been doing in recent years, so to see Xbox join that group with Infinite would not be much of a surprise. </string>
    <string name="Forza">After being airdropped from a cargo plane in an AMG One, I arrive at the festival site to fanfare and fireworks. The organisers are delighted—their superstar is finally here—and to celebrate they offer me a choice of starting car. I leave the site and head to my first race in a Corvette Stingray Coupe. This is not how racing games are supposed to start. I should be battling for wins in some aging hatchback, dreaming of the day I can get behind the wheel of something sleek and fast. Instead, I am being handed a 500 horsepower supercar to tear through the streets of Mexico.

It makes sense, though. Forza Horizon 5 does not need to do what other racing games would do. It just needs to be a Forza Horizon game, because Horizons brand of vehicular playground antics has no serious rival.

Sim racing is a competitive field, but on the more arcade side its not looking so healthy. Burnout Paradise showed the promise of open world racing back in 2008, but, for whatever reason, EA never followed it up. The Need for Speed series ping ponged between varying degrees of arcade and simulation for years, never carving out a singular identity for itself. Dirt is similarly confused the strength of its Dirt Rally spin offs leaving the parent series unsure of what its meant to be. Forza Horizon has not so much pulled ahead of the pack as its already finished the race and is now free to amuse itself.</string>
    <string name="Elder">February 2022 was already packed full of big game releases. Now FromSoftware has added another to the list, delaying Elden Ring a month from its original January 21, 2022 release date. In the meantime, the game will get a player demo next month as grainy in-development footage continues to leak online.

Elden Ring, the open-world successor to the Dark Souls series, will now come out on February 25, 2022 to give FromSoftware more time to work on it. The depth amp strategic freedom of the game exceeded initial expectations, the studio announced on Twitter today. In November, it will host a Closed Network Test showing select players the “opening hours” of the full game.After being announced at E3 2019, Elden Ring went quiet for a while, making fans desperate for more info as some worried that the games development may have hit a brick wall. Lots of leaked footage and rumored delays later, FromSoftware announced a January 2022 release date at this years Summer Game Fest.</string>
    <string name="COD">Vanguard wont join the pantheon of Call of Duty games, but its a decent stop-gap for those waiting for Modern Warfares return.

It feels like a stop-gap year for Call of Duty. Developer Sledgehammer Games finds itself sandwiched in-between the mega sub-brands that are Modern Warfare and Black Ops, and has produced fun filler for fans to be getting on with. There nothing wrong or bad or off-putting in this return to World War 2, but Vanguard does nothing exceptionally.That return to World War 2 feels like a boring choice of setting. Sledgehammers excellent Call of Duty: WW2 opened the door to the long-running shooter series for me, and after walking through I have spent thousands of hours in this new Call of Duty metaverse (sorry). But I struggle to get excited for another Call of Duty set in World War 2 - despite Sledgehammers best effort to put a spin on storytelling.

</string>
    <string name="battlefield">EA Play and Game Pass subscribers who are not looking to shell out the money for a pre-order of Battlefield 2042 will get a chance to try out the game, thanks to an early access trial.

Subscribers to those two services will get to play a ten-hour, early access trial of Battlefield 2042 starting on Nov. 12, Electronic Arts and developer DICE said on Wednesday. Subscribers will get access to both the Open Beta and the 10-hour trial.

EA Play Pro subscribers, as well as anyone has pre-ordered the Gold or Ultimate editions of Battlefield 2042, will get early access to the full game on Nov. 12.

Also on Wednesday, EA released a new Battlefield 2042 trailer showing more of the Battlefield Portal, which allows players to design their own custom matches. In October, the developers revealed more details about the games third big game mode, called Hazard Zone.

Battlefield 2042 is scheduled to be officially released on Nov. 19 to PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X, and Windows PC.</string>
</resources>